Good morning.
早上好。
When I was a little boy,
在我小时候
I had an experience that changed my life,
有一个经历改变了我的一生，
and is in fact why I'm here today.
这也是我站在这的原因。
That one moment
在那一刻
profoundly affected how I think about
我对艺术、设计和工程的看法
art, design and engineering.
被深深地改变了。
As background, I was fortunate enough to grow up
关于背景，我很幸运地生长在
in a family of loving and talented artists
位于世界最大城市之一的
in one of the world's great cities.
一个充满爱和有才艺术家的家庭。
My dad, John Ferren, who died when I was 15,
我的父亲，John Ferren, 在我15岁的时候去世了，
was an artist by both passion and profession,
他曾是一个热爱艺术的艺术家，
as is my mom, Rae.
同我母亲Rae一样。
He was one of the New York School
他曾是纽约抽象表现主义画家
abstract expressionists who,
的一员，
together with his contemporaries,
他和他的同龄人一起，
invented American modern art,
创造了美国现代艺术，
and contributed to moving the American zeitgeist
并且为在20世纪把美国的时代思潮
towards modernism in the 20th century.
推向现代主义做出了贡献。
Isn't it remarkable that, after thousands of years
在具象派艺术盛行了几千年以后，
of people doing mostly representational art,
相比之下，
that modern art, comparatively speaking,
现代艺术就像只存在了15分钟，
is about 15 minutes old,
如今卻非常普及，
yet now pervasive.
这难道不是卓越非凡的吗？
As with many other important innovations,
其它许多重要的创新也是如此，
those radical ideas required no new technology,
那些激进的理念无需任何新技术，
just fresh thinking and a willingness to experiment,
只需要创新的思维和敢于尝试的意愿，
plus resiliency in the face of near-universal criticism
加上能够承受几乎所有人批判与反对
and rejection.
的恢复能力。
In our home, art was everywhere.
在我们家里，艺术无处不在。
It was like oxygen,
它就像氧气，
around us and necessary for life.
环绕着我们，也是我们生命的需要。
As I watched him paint,
我看着父亲绘画的时候，
Dad taught me that art
他教导我说艺术
was not about being decorative,
并不是用来装饰的，
but was a different way of communicating ideas,
而是交流思想的另一种方法，
and in fact one that could bridge the worlds
确切的说，这种方法可以把知识和见解
of knowledge and insight.
这两个世界给联系起来。
Given this rich artistic environment,
在这样一个充满艺术气息的环境里，
you'd assume that I would have been compelled
你会认为我会被迫着
to go into the family business,
去从事家族企业，
but no.
但你错了。
I followed the path of most kids
我像那些生来就是为了
who are genetically programmed
逼家长们发疯的小孩子一样，
to make their parents crazy.
选择了另一条路。
I had no interest in becoming an artist,
我对成为一名艺术家毫无兴趣，
certainly not a painter.
更别谈画家。
What I did love was electronics and machines --
我当时爱的是电器和机械--
taking them apart, building new ones,
把他们拆开，建造新的，
and making them work.
并让它们运作。
Fortunately, my family also had engineers in it,
幸运的是，我的家庭中也有工程师，
and with my parents,
他们和我的父母，
these were my first role models.
都是我最早的榜样。
What they all had in common
他们所有人的共同点
was they worked very, very hard.
就是都非常努力地工作。
My grandpa owned and operated a sheet metal
我的祖父曾在布鲁克林拥有一个
kitchen cabinet factory in Brooklyn.
他自己运作的钣金橱柜厂。
On weekends, we would go together to Cortlandt Street,
在周末的时候，我们会一起去Cortlandt 街,
which was New York City's radio row.
现在已经是纽约城的广播站了。
There we would explore massive piles
在那里我们会探索成堆的
of surplus electronics,
盈余的电子产品，
and for a few bucks bring home treasures
和一些物美价廉的宝贝，
like Norden bombsights
比如诺登投弹瞄准器
and parts from the first IBM tube-based computers.
和IBM最早生产的管座电脑的零件。
I found these objects both useful and fascinating.
我发现这些东西很有用也很吸引人。
I learned about engineering and how things worked,
我认识了工程与一些东西的运作原理，
not at school
不是从学校，
but by taking apart and studying
而是通过拆卸和研究
these fabulously complex devices.
这些极度复杂的装置。
I did this for hours every day,
我每天都要在这上面花上好几个小时，
apparently avoiding electrocution.
显然还要防止自己被电死。
Life was good.
美好的生活。
However, every summer, sadly,
然而令人悲哀的是，每个夏天，
the machines got left behind
那些机器都会被抛下，
while my parents and I traveled overseas
因为我父母会带着我出国
to experience history, art and design.
去体验历史、艺术和设计。
We visited the great museums and historic buildings
我们参观了位于欧洲和中东的
of both Europe and the Middle East,
大博物馆和历史性建筑，
but to encourage my growing interest
但为了激励我对科学和科技
in science and technology,
日益增长的兴趣，
they would simply drop me off in places
他们会简单的把我放到
like the London Science Museum,
像伦敦科学博物馆之类的地方，
where I would wander endlessly for hours by myself
在那里我会花几个小时无止尽的独自游走，
studying the history of science and technology.
学习与科学和科技相关的历史。
Then, when I was about nine years old,
然后，在我差不多九岁的时候，
we went to Rome.
我们到了罗马。
On one particularly hot summer day,
在一个格外炎热的夏天，
we visited a drum-shaped building that from the outside
我们参观了一个外观并不起眼的
was not particularly interesting.
鼓形建筑。
My dad said it was called the Pantheon,
我父亲告诉我它被称为万神殿，
a temple for all of the gods.
一个为诸神而建的神殿。
It didn't look all that special from the outside,
从外面它看起来并不特别，
as I said, but when we walked inside,
就像我之前说的， 但当我们走进去的时候，
I was immediately struck by three things:
我瞬间被三样东西震惊了：
First of all, it was pleasantly cool
首先，室内是令人舒服的凉爽，
despite the oppressive heat outside.
尽管室外闷热。
It was very dark, the only source of light
这里面非常暗，唯一的光线来源
being an big open hole in the roof.
是屋顶的一个大洞。
Dad explained that this wasn't a big open hole,
父亲解释说这不是一个大洞，
but it was called the oculus,
而是被称为眼洞窗，
an eye to the heavens.
天堂的一只眼睛。
And there was something about this place,
还有，这个地方有些东西，
I didn't know why, that just felt special.
我不知道为什么，就是感觉很特别。
As we walked to the center of the room,
当我们走到房间的中央，
I looked up at the heavens through the oculus.
我通过眼洞窗仰望天堂。
This was the first church that I'd been to
这是我到过的第一个
that provided an unrestricted view
为神与人之间提供了
between God and man.
直接视野的教堂。
But I wondered, what about when it rained?
但我当时好奇，如果下雨了怎么办？
Dad may have called this an oculus,
虽然我父亲把它称为眼洞窗，
but it was, in fact, a big hole in the roof.
但它实际上就是房顶的一个大洞。
I looked down and saw floor drains
我低头看到了地面的排水管
had been cut into the stone floor.
是切在地面的石头上的。
As I became more accustomed to the dark,
当我变得更适应于黑暗，
I was able to make out details of the floor
我逐渐能够看清地板与周围墙壁
and the surrounding walls.
上的细节了。
No big deal here, just the same statuary stuff
这儿没什么大不了的，只是一些在罗马
that we'd seen all over Rome.
随处可见的雕像罢了。
In fact, it looked like the Appian Way
实际上，它看上去像亚庇古道，
marble salesman showed up
那个大理石推销员带着他的样本书出现，
with his sample book, showed it to Hadrian,
展示给了哈德良，
and Hadrian said, "We'll take all of it."
然后哈德良说："我们全都要了”的地方。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But the ceiling was amazing.
但天花板还是很惊艳的。
It looked like a Buckminster Fuller geodesic dome.
它看上去像Buckminster Fuller的一个穹顶建筑。
I'd seen these before,
我曾经见过这些，
and Bucky was friends with my dad.
Bucky也是我父亲的朋友。
It was modern, high-tech, impressive,
它很现代、 高科技的、 令人印象深刻，
a huge 142-foot clear span
142 英尺的巨大净跨距
which, not coincidentally, was exactly its height.
也并非巧合的，刚好是是它自身的高度。
I loved this place.
我爱这个地方。
It was really beautiful and unlike anything I'd ever seen before,
它非常的美丽而且是我前所未见的，
so I asked my dad, "When was this built?"
所以我问我父亲："这是什么时候修建的?"
He said, "About 2,000 years ago."
他说："大约 2000 年前"。
And I said, "No, I mean, the roof."
我说："不，我的意思是，屋顶"。
You see, I assumed that this was a modern roof
是这样，我把它默认为一个现代的屋顶，
that had been put on because the original
把它放在那是因为原来的屋顶
was destroyed in some long-past war.
在很久以前的一场战争中被摧毁了。
He said, "It's the original roof."
他说，"它就是原始的屋顶"。
That moment changed my life,
那一刻，我的一生被改变了，
and I can remember it as if it were yesterday.
而且依然令我记忆犹新。
For the first time, I realized people were smart
这是我第一次意识到人类在2000多年前
2,000 years ago. (Laughter)
就很聪明了。（笑声）
This had never crossed my mind.
这点我以前从未想到。
I mean, to me, the pyramids at Giza,
我是说，在我看来，吉萨的金字塔，
we visited those the year before,
我们去年参观过，
and sure they're impressive, nice enough design,
它们确实令人印象深刻、很好的设计，
but look, give me an unlimited budget,
不过，给我无限的预算、
20,000 to 40,000 laborers, and about 10 to 20 years
两万到四万个工人和大概10 至20 年
to cut and drag stone blocks  across the countryside,
在乡村里切割和拖动石头块，
and I'll build you pyramids too.
我也能给你修出金字塔。
But no amount of brute force
但是再多的蛮力也无法
gets you the dome of the Pantheon,
创造出万神殿的圆顶，
not 2,000 years ago, nor today.
两千年前不行，现在也不行。
And incidentally, it is still the largest
顺便说一下，它到目前为止仍是
unreinforced concrete dome that's ever been built.
历史上最大的未加固的混凝土圆顶。
To build the Pantheon took some miracles.
万神殿的修建包含了一些奇迹。
By miracles, I mean things that are
我所说的奇迹是指
technically barely possible,
技术上几乎不可能的、
very high-risk, and might not be
极度高的风险、并且可能
actually accomplishable at this moment in time,
在这一时间段根本无法完成的，
certainly not by you.
当然更不是由你。
For example, here are some of the Pantheon's miracles.
例如，下面是万神殿的一些奇迹。
To make it even structurally possible,
仅仅要让它的结构可行，
they had to invent super-strong concrete,
他们不得不创造超强的混凝土，
and to control weight,
还得控制重量，
varied the density of the aggregate
这是通过在搭建圆顶的过程中
as they worked their way up the dome.
不断改变混合物的密度而达到的。
For strength and lightness, the dome structure
对于强度和轻度，圆顶的结构
used five rings of coffers,
使用了花格镶板的五个圆环，
each of diminishing size,
每个的大小递减，
which imparts a dramatic forced perspective
因此为设计赋予了一个
to the design.
引人注目的强迫视图。
It was wonderfully cool inside
它里面非常凉快
because of its huge thermal mass,
的原因是源于它庞大的热质量，
natural convection of air rising up
自然对流的空气上升
through the oculus,
通过眼洞窗，
and a Venturi effect when wind blows across
并在风吹过屋顶时
the top of the building.
产生文丘里效应。
I discovered for the first time that light itself
我第一次发现光线本身
has substance.
是有实质的。
The shaft of light beaming through the oculus
透过眼洞窗的光束
was both beautiful and palpable,
是美丽的，也是可感知的，
and I realized for the first time
并且让我第一次意识到
that light could be designed.
光是可以被设计的。
Further, that of all of the forms of design,
进一步而言，所有形式的设计，
visual design,
视觉设计，
they were all kind of irrelevant without it,
如果没有它貌似就有些不切实际了，
because without light, you can't see any of them.
因为如果没有光，那些东西你都看不见。
I also realized that I wasn't the first person
我还意识到我并不是第一个
to think that this place was really special.
认为这个地方很特别的人。
It survived gravity, barbarians, looters, developers
它经受住了重力、 野蛮人、 掠夺者、 开发人员
and the ravages of time to become
和时间的蹂躏，从而成为了
what I believe is the longest
我相信是历史上
continuously occupied building in history.
被持续使用最久的建筑。
Largely because of that visit,
主要是因为那次参观，
I came to understand that,
我开始明白了，
contrary to what I was being told in school,
与学校教导我的相反，
the worlds of art and design
艺术和设计的世界
were not, in fact, incompatible
事实上并不是
with science and engineering.
不跟科学与工程兼容的。
I realized, when combined,
我意识到，当两者结合时，
you could create things that were amazing
你可以创造惊出人的东西，
that couldn't be done in either domain alone.
而这些只在单个领域是完成不了的。
But in school, with few exceptions,
但在学校，除了少数例外，
they were treated as separate worlds,
它们被视为独立的世界，
and they still are.
现在依然如此。
My teachers told me that I had to get serious
我老师说我必须正经地
and focus on one or the other.
选择一个领域。
However, urging me to specialize
然而，催促我专门化
only caused me to really  appreciate those polymaths
只使得我更加感激那些博学者
like Michelangelo, Leonardo da Vinci,
例如 达 · 芬奇、 米开朗基罗、
Benjamin Franklin,
本杰明 · 富兰克林，
people who did exactly the opposite.
那些做了完全相反的人。
And this led me to embrace
这让我接受
and want to be in both worlds.
并且想要存在于两个世界。
So then how do these projects of unprecedented creative vision and technical complexity
那么这些前所未有的创造性视野 和复杂的技术
like the Pantheon actually happen?
比如万神殿，是怎样出现的呢？
Someone themselves, perhaps Hadrian,
一个人自身，或许同哈德良一样，
needed a brilliant creative vision.
需要绝妙的创造性视野。
They also needed the storytelling and leadership skills
他们还需要能够资助并且执行它的
necessary to fund and execute it,
叙述能力与领导能力，
and a mastery of science and technology
和对科学与技术的掌握
with the ability and knowhow
加上能够把现有的创新推动更远
to push existing innovations even farther.
的能力与诀窍。
It is my belief that to create these rare game changers
我相信这些稀有的颠覆者
requires you to pull off at least five miracles.
都至少需要创造五个奇迹。
The problem is, no matter how talented,
问题是，无论你是多么有才、
rich or smart you are,
富于或是聪明，
you only get one to one and a half miracles.
你只能得到一个至一个半的奇迹。
That's it. That's the quota.
就这么多，这就是你的限额。
Then you run out of time, money, enthusiasm,
然后你就会耗尽你的时间、金钱、热情，
whatever.
无论你有的是什么。
Remember, most people can't even imagine
记住，大多数人连想都不敢想
one of these technical miracles,
这些技术奇迹的其中一个，
and you need at least five to make a Pantheon.
而你至少需要实现五个 才能建成万神殿
In my experience, these rare visionaries
以我的经验，在这些罕见的预言家中，
who can think across the worlds of art,
能够跨越艺术、设计、
design and engineering
和工程的世界思考的人，
have the ability to notice
就有能力察觉
when others have provided enough of the miracles
什么时候其他人提供了足够多的奇迹
to bring the goal within reach.
以至于目标是可以实现的了。
Driven by the clarity of their vision,
被他们透彻的远见所驱使，
they summon the courage and determination
他们鼓了起勇气和决心
to deliver the remaining miracles
来实现剩余的那些奇迹，
and they often take what other people think to be
并且他们往往把他人认为是
insurmountable obstacles
无法逾越的障碍
and turn them into features.
转化成为特色。
Take the oculus of the Pantheon.
以万神殿的眼洞窗为例。
By insisting that it be in the design,
由于坚持把它归于设计之中，
it meant you couldn't use much of the structural technology
就意味着你不能大量运用为 罗马的半圆拱形门
that had been developed for Roman arches.
所研制的建筑科技。
However, by instead embracing it
然而，通过去欣然接受它
and rethinking weight and stress distribution,
并且反思重量与压力的分布，
they came up with a design that only works
他们找到了一种设计，
if there's a big hole in the roof.
只在当屋顶有个大洞的时候才适用。
That done, you now get the aesthetic
事成之后，你就得到了光线、降温，
and design benefits of light, cooling
关键是那个能与天堂直接相对
and that critical direct connection with the heavens.
的审美与设计上的好处。
Not bad.
还不错。
These people not only believed
这些人不只是相信
that the impossible can be done,
不可能可以被实现，
but that it must be done.
而是必须被实现。
Enough ancient history.
远古的历史就说到这。
What are some recent examples of innovations
当代有哪些关于
that combine creative design
结合了创意性设计
and technological advances in a way so profound
和科技进步的创新，如此深刻，
that they will be remembered
它们直到一千年以后
a thousand years from now?
还会被记住？
Well, putting a man on the moon was a good one,
说起来，把一个人送上月球是挺好，
and returning him safely to Earth wasn't bad either.
让他安全地回来也不错。
Talk about one giant leap:
谈到巨大的飞跃：
It's hard to imagine a more profound moment
在人类历史上很难想象到
in human history
一个比我们初次离开地球
than when we first left our world
去踏入另一个世界
to set foot on another.
更深刻的时刻了。
So what came after the moon?
登月后还有什么呢？
One is tempted to say that today's pantheon
有人禁不住会说，如今的万神殿
is the Internet,
是互联网，
but I actually think that's quite wrong,
但我确认为这不太对，
or at least it's only part of the story.
或者说这最多只是故事的一部分。
The Internet isn't a Pantheon.
互联网不是一个万神殿。
It's more like the invention of concrete:
它更像是混凝土的发明：
important, absolutely necessary
很重要、对建造万神殿
to build the Pantheon,
有绝对的必要，
and enduring,
并且让它持久，
but entirely insufficient by itself.
但单独拿出来是没有用的。
However, just as the technology of concrete
然而，就像混凝土技术
was critical in realization of the Pantheon,
是实现万神殿的关键，
new designers will use the technologies of the Internet
新的设计师们将使用互联网技术
to create novel concepts that will endure.
来打造新颖，并且能够持久的概念。
The smartphone is a perfect example.
智能手机是一个完美的例子。
Soon the majority of people on the planet
很快，地球上绝大多数的人
will have one,
都将拥有一台，
and the idea of connecting everyone
然后把每个人跟知识与他人
to both knowledge and each other will endure.
联系起来的点子就会持久。
So what's next?
那么，下一个是什么?
What imminent advance will be the equivalent of the Pantheon?
有那些临近了的发展将能与万 神殿相提并论？
Thinking about this,
想到这里，
I rejected many very plausible
我淘汰了很多非常值得鼓励
and dramatic breakthroughs to come,
和戏剧性的潜在突破，
such as curing cancer.
比如治疗癌症。
Why? Because Pantheons are anchored
为什么呢？因为万神殿被固定为了
in designed physical objects,
被设计出的有形物体，
ones that inspire by simply seeing
是那些人们单是通过观看和体验
and experiencing them,
就能受到启发的东西，
and will continue to do so indefinitely.
并且会这样无期限地延续下去。
It is a different kind of language, like art.
它是一种不同的语言，就像艺术。
These other vital contributions that extend life
另外这些为延长寿命和减轻病痛 所做出的贡献
and relieve suffering are, of course, critical,
当然也是至关重要，
and fantastic,
并且精妙绝伦的，
but they're part of the continuum of
但它们是我们对
our overall knowledge and technology,
知识和科技的总体认识的一部分延伸，
like the Internet.
就像互联网。
So what is next?
那么，下一个是什么?
Perhaps counterintuitively,
或许与直觉相反，
I'm guessing it's a visionary idea
我猜这是一个富有远见的想法，
from the late 1930s
从 30 年代末开始，
that's been revived every decade since:
每十年都会经历复兴：
autonomous vehicles.
自动驾驶汽车。
Now you're thinking, give me a break.
你现在会想，别逗我了。
How can a fancy version of cruise control
不同版本的巡航控制怎么可能
be profound?
是意义深远的呢？
Look, much of our world
是这样，我们世界的一大部分
has been designed around  roads and transportation.
都是围绕着道路与交通设计的。
These were as essential to the success
这些东西是必不可少的，
of the Roman Empire
对于罗马帝国的成就，
as the interstate highway system
和作为州际公路系统
to the prosperity and development
对于美国的
of the United States.
繁荣与发展。
Today, these roads that interconnect our world
今天，这些把我们的世界连接起来的道路
are dominated by cars and trucks
以汽车和卡车占主导地位，
that have remained largely unchanged
这些东西在100年间在大体上
for 100 years.
没有太大的改变。
Although perhaps not obvious today,
虽然在今天可能并不明显，
autonomous vehicles will be the key technology
自驾车辆将是很关键的技术，
that enables us to redesign our cities
它能让我们重新设计我们的城市
and, by extension, civilization.
还有相关的，文明。
Here's why:
原因如下：
Once they become ubiquitous,
一旦它们普及起来，
each year, these vehicles will save
每年，这些车辆都将拯救
tens of thousands of lives in the United States alone
成千上万的生命，这仅仅在美国，
and a million globally.
在全世界将是数千万。
Automotive energy consumption and air pollution
汽车产业所消耗的能源
will be cut dramatically.
和污染的空气将大幅削减。
Much of the road congestion
很多在我们城市间
in and out of our cities will disappear.
发生的道路挤塞将会消失。
They will enable compelling new concepts
他们会允许一些令人叹服的新概念，
in how we design cities, work,
影响我们对城市、工作，
and the way we live.
和我们的生活方式的设计。
We will get where we're going faster
我们将能更快地到达目的地，
and society will recapture vast amounts
社会也将会夺回大量
of lost productivity
为了治理交通污染
now spent sitting in traffic basically polluting.
而失去了的生产力。
But why now? Why do we think this is ready?
但为什么是现在？我们为什么认为已经准备好了？
Because over the last 30 years,
因为在过去的30年间，
people from outside the automotive industry
从事汽车行业以外的人
have spent countless billions
花费了数亿的资金
creating the needed miracles,
创造所需要的奇迹，
but for entirely different purposes.
但目的确完全不同。
It took folks like DARPA, universities,
这是通过像DARPA、大学， （DARPA：美国国防部高级研究计划局）
and companies completely outside of the automotive industry
和与汽车产业完全无关的 企业的那些人
to notice that if you were clever about it,
来注意到，如果你机灵点，
autonomy could be done now.
自动驾驶现在可以实现了。
So what are the five miracles needed for autonomous vehicles?
那么自驾车辆所需的五个奇迹是什么？
One, you need to know
第一，你需要知道
where you are and exactly what time it is.
你所处的位置与现在的时间。
This was solved neatly by the GPS system,
这由GPS系统完美地解决了，
Global Positioning System,
全球定位系统，
that the U.S. Government put in place.
由美国政府落实了。
You need to know where all the roads are,
你需要知道所有的路都在哪里、
what the rules are, and where you're going.
有什么规则，和你要去哪。
The various needs of personal navigation systems,
对于私人导航系统的各种需求，
in-car navigation systems,
车载导航系统，
and web-based maps address this.
和网络的地图解决了这个问题。
You must have near-continuous communication
你必须拥有
with high-performance computing networks
与高性能计算网络和与附近其他人的
and with others nearby
几乎无间断的交流
to understand their intent.
才能了解他们的意图。
The wireless technologies developed for mobile devices,
为移动设备所开发的无线技术，
with some minor modifications,
加上一些小的修改，
are completely suitable to solve this.
完全可以解决这个问题。
You'll probably want some restricted roadways
若要开始，你可能需要一些
to get started
受限的道路，
that both society and its lawyers
从而让社会和律师们
agree are safe to use for this.
都同意它的使用是安全的。
This will start with the HOV lanes
这将从高乘载车道开始
and move from there.
然后扩张。
But finally, you need to recognize
但你最终需要辨认
people, signs and objects.
人、 路标和物体。
Machine vision, special sensors, and high-performance computing
机器视觉、特殊传感器，与高性能计算
can do a lot of this,
都可以做到一大部分，
but it turns out a lot is not good enough
但事实证明一大部分是不够的，
when your family is on board.
因为你的家人的安全也由它掌握着。
Occasionally, humans will  need to do sense-making.
人们将时不时地需要开动脑筋。
For this, you might actually have to wake up
为此，你可能真的要去把你的乘客叫醒
your passenger and ask them what the hell
并且询问他们
that big lump is in the middle of the road.
马路中间的那一大块是什么鬼东西。
Not so bad, and it will give us a sense of purpose
这不算太糟糕， 而且会在这个新的世界
in this new world.
赋予我们一种使命感
Besides, once the first drivers explain
再说了，一旦第一个司机解释
to their confused car
给他们困惑的车说
that the giant chicken at the fork in the road
那个挡在分岔口的巨型小鸡
is actually a restaurant,
其实是一家餐厅，
and it's okay to keep driving,
并告诉它没关系，继续开车，
every other car on the surface of the Earth
从那时开始，地球表面上一半的车辆
will know that from that point on.
都会了解这一点。
Five miracles, mostly delivered,
五个奇迹，差不多都到齐了，
and now you just need a clear vision
而现在你唯独需要一个清晰的视野，
of a better world filled with autonomous vehicles
能看到一个遍地是自驾车辆的世界，
with seductively beautiful  and new functional designs
它们的设计散发着极具诱惑性的美丽 并拥有全新的性能，
plus a lot of money and hard work
再加上大量的钱和辛苦的劳动，
to bring it home.
才能把它变成现实。
The beginning is now only a handful of years away,
它的开始相对现在只有几年的距离了，
and I predict that autonomous vehicles
而且我预测自驾车辆
will permanently change our world
将永久地改变我们的世界，
over the next several decades.
就在接下来的几十年间。
In conclusion, I've come to believe
作为总结，我开始相信
that the ingredients for the next Pantheons
建造下一个万神殿的材料
are all around us,
就在我们身边，
just waiting for visionary people
只是在等待有远见的人，
with the broad knowledge,
加上他们广泛的知识、
multidisciplinary skills,
多学科的技能，
and intense passion
和想要运用它们
to harness them to make their dreams a reality.
从而把梦想变成现实的强烈热情。
But these people don't spontaneously
但这些人不是自然地
pop into existence.
就蹦出来了。
They need to be nurtured and encouraged
他们需要从小开始
from when they're little kids.
就加以培育和鼓励。
We need to love them and help them
我们要爱护他们并且帮助他们
discover their passions.
发现他们的热情所在。
We need to encourage them to work hard
我们需要去鼓励他们努力工作
and help them understand that failure
并帮助他们理解失败
is a necessary ingredient for success,
是成功的必要因素，
as is perseverance.
毅力也是如此。
We need to help them to find their own role models,
我们需要帮助他们找到自己的榜样，
and give them the confidence to believe in themselves
并给他们能够相信自己
and to believe that anything is possible,
和一切皆有可能的信心，
and just as my grandpa did when he took me shopping for surplus,
正如我爷爷的带着我去淘 盈余商品的时候，
and just as my parents did
正如我的父母带我
when they took me to science museums,
去科学博物馆的时候，
we need to encourage them to find their own path,
我们需要鼓励他们去找自己的路，
even if it's very different from our own.
即使它与我们自己的不同。
But a cautionary note:
但要警惕的是：
We also need to periodically pry them away
我们还需要定期地把他们
from their modern miracles,
与现代的奇迹分开，
the computers, phones, tablets,
比如计算机、 手机、 平板电脑、
game machines and TVs,
游戏机和电视机，
take them out into the sunlight
带他们去沐浴阳光
so they can experience both the natural
从而让他们有机会体验自然
and design wonders of our world,
与我们世界、我们星球，
our planet and our civilization.
和我们文明的设计奇观。
If we don't, they won't understand
如果我们不这样，他们就无法理解
what these precious things are
这些珍贵的东西是什么，
that someday they will be resopnsible
这些将是他们在未来某天有义务
for protecting and improving.
去保护和改善的东西。
We also need them to understand
我们还需要他们理解
something that doesn't seem adequately appreciated
一件在我们越发依赖科技的世界里
in our increasingly tech-dependent world,
似乎没有被充分领会的事，
that art and design
就是艺术与设计
are not luxuries,
不是奢侈品，
nor somehow incompatible
也不是跟科学与工程
with science and engineering.
无法兼容的。
They are in fact essential to what makes us special.
事实上，只有它们才能让我们如此特别。
Someday, if you get the chance,
某一天，如果你有机会，
perhaps you can take your kids
或许你可以把你的孩子
to the actual Pantheon,
带到真正的万神殿，
as we will our daughter Kira,
就像我们会把我们的女儿Kira
to experience firsthand
带去亲身体验
the power of that astonishing design,
那令人震惊的设计所带来的力量，
which on one otherwise unremarkable day in Rome,
这让在罗马本是平凡普通的一天，
reached 2,000 years into the future
延伸到了未来两千年后，
to set the course for my life.
并为我的人生设定了方向。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）